Guide to the Abraham Yates, Jr. papers, 1604-1825 [bulk 1760-1796]
The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division.
- ALPHABETICAL LIST
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany
    Refers to Yates' standing for the coming Election. "The Camps will not move to an Election without being payed for their time at 4 o/ pr. man. The Gentlemen of the other Side have wrote me for my Interest but have not had opportunity to answer them. Sir William I find has, which by the by is not so very agreeable to them". Autograph letter signed 2 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston, Feb. 8, 1761.
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr. unsigned draft of letter in his autograph. "As my friend Mr. Ab. Yates wrote me the 4 Current that he Intended to Stand Candidate & desired my Interest I could not refuse him". This draft is a copy of a letter sent by Livingston, February 8, 1761
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates Junr., Merchant att Albany, Refers to dishonorable methods used at Elections. "I see you are like to have new Troubles upon your Corporation for encroachments by the Township of Schenectady". autog, February 16, 1761
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., Addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates Junr., Merchant att Albany. Refers to Yates failure at the recent Election. "You have now experienced what dependence there is on that frail Creature Called man. I hope however. you have not paid t, March 26, 1761
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Refers to Yates' desire to be appointed Sheriff on the death of the person, then holding that office. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston, May 11, 1761
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Mr. James Stevenson, Merchant In Albany. "I have ordered my young man to go up with the pittejagoe & to Carry as much bar Iron: for you as it will conveniently load". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor, July 9, 1761
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. in Albany. Refers to Mr. Stevenson some business with the Sheriff. "As head Quarters is now in your City, doubtless you have all the news Running, as I here am barren must Entreat you to Communica, July 21, 1761
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. att Albany. "I was in great hopes that after the Reduction of all Canada arbitrary power and all other Illegal proceedings by the Gentlemen of the army would have been at an end. You tell me a pie, July 28, 1761
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. att Albany, Refers to the disposition of the troops then stationed on Staten Island; to the War on the Continent; mentions Col, Grant, sir William Johnson & Gen. Monckton. "I have not heard that a, August 5, 1761
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, att Albany, Wishes Hendrick Bogart to come down to put a new bottom in his Sloop. "The fleet is Saild I heard for Barbados their to make the randevous for getherlng the whole fleet & army togethe, December 2, 1761
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., attorney at law In Albany. An interesting letter relating to affairs in Germany, Spain, Denmark, Russia also commenting on domestic news. "By the Speach of his Honr., to the Assembly, December 8, 1761
  - Livingston., Robert, Junr, addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., Attorney at Law In Albany, Referring to a "white Seader Swamp" & enclosing a letter of Yates' relating to Van Bergen's land. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston, February 8, 1762
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., attorney at Law in Albany. Referring to the unpleasant feeling existing between the late & present Mayors & mentioning the sale of lots in the Saratoga Patent. autograph letter signed 3 p., March 4, 1762
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., attorney at Law In Albany. Mentions Killiaan De Ridder, Mr, Lydius, Mr. Stevenson & Mr. Silvester. "A Spanish War seems to threaten & prhaps we are on the Eve of it. It's true we are at pr, March 13, 1762
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Attorney at Law In Albany, Refers to the request of the English Presbyterians for a meeting-house, where the "Grenary" now stands. "I Congratulate you on the Reduction of Martinico, this i, April 19, 1752
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Attorney at Law In Albany. "I want to hear how our army at Martinico is to be disposed of for the Summer Season and what other Expeditions we are to undertake". autograph letter signed 1 p, May 8, 1762
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany. Referring to trouble in the church & mentioning the birth of a child in Yates' family. "I am just going to a bon Fire I have Caused to be Erected as a testimony of our Joy on th, September 13, 1762
  - Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr, Referring to Col, Van Rensselaer 's meeting with his tenants and the validity of their leases. Also mentions Mr, Jeremiah Van Rensselaer, autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston, December 2, 1762
  - Loan Office Endorsed: "Return for October, 1782", copy. D. 2 p. quarto
  - Lott, Abraham, to The Honorable Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. of the Senate at Poughkeepsie. Refers to his confinement in Goal & a Memorial which he wished to have laid before the Legislature. autograph letter signed 1 p folio, dated New York Goal, January 22, 1788
  - Low, Isaac (Chairman), to Mr. Jacob Lansingh, Chairman of the Committee of the City and County of Albany. Relating to some goods forwarded to Mr. Abraham Schuyler & Mr. - Andrew McFarlin. autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated New York, December 15, 1774
  - McCall, J, (Secretary), to Abraham Yates Esqr., Commissioner of the C. L. O. for the State of New York. Concerning a Bill of Exchange. L. R. 1 p. quarto, dated Office of Finance, October 23, 1732
  - McKay, Alexander, addressed to Mr, Abraham Yates Esqr. Attorney at Law in Albany. His bill against Jno. McFall for the amount of which he brings suit. D. S. 1 p. folio, dated February 1765
  - McKerlie, John. His affidavit concerning Ensign Howard. "The people seem to be suspicious of General Schuyler and his proceedings and that they were also suspicious that the Provisions going up were for the use of the King's Troops". D. S. 1 p. folio, dated May 18, 1776
  - Metcalfe, George. Acknowledgment of himself as author of an article in the Federal Herald Feb, 18, 1788. derogatory to Abraham Yates Junr. & admitting the falseness of the same. Also signed by Thos, Q. Witbeck & Abm, Reynolds. A. D. S. 1 p. folio, dated A, April 25, 1789
  - Milligan, James (Compt. of the Treasury), copy of document sent to The Honorable The Board of Treasury. Refers to the settlement of Abraham Yates Junr's accounts as Loan Officer. 4 p. large folio, dated Camp- troller's Office, December 9, 1786
  - Mohawney, John, to Abraham Yates Junr. Esq., Albany. An order to pay to Cornelius Glen the amount due him. Signed by Matthew Visscher, Abraham Yates Junr. & Cornelius Glen. D. signed by his mark, dated Albany, September 30, 1772
  - Morris, Robert, to his Excellency The Governor & Commander in Chief of the State of New York. Concerning the account of the United States against the State of New York. "Your Excellency must be sensible of the Impracticability of carrying on the War unles, July 16, 1781
  - Morris, Robert, to Governor Clinton. Concerning the account against the State of New York for specific supplies & asking information of Gov. Clinton on various points. autograph letter signed 5 p. folio, dated Philadelphia, July 25, 1781
  - Morris, Robert, probably addressed to Gov. Clinton, Pointing out the erroneous ideas held by Americans as to the financial aid given by France & Spain & Holland to the United States. "Not a single State has acknowledged our Independence except France". Pa, October 19, 1731
  - Morris, Robert (probably), part of a letter presumably sent by Morris either to the President of Congress or the Governor of the State of New York, explaining at length his scheme for funding the national debt. D. 24 p. quarto, dated Office of Finance, July 29, 1782
  - Morris, Robert. copy of Documentä to the Commissioners for Settling Accounts of the States. Copy made by Wm. Barber. The whole is endorsed: - "Queres. proposed by the Auditors appointed to settle the Accts. of the States of Maryland & New Jersey with the, September 7, 1782
  - Morris, Robert, to Abraham Yates Esq., Loan Officer for New York, "You will be pleased to transmit me all the Bills of Exchange now in your Office". L. S. 1 p. quarto, dated Office of Finance, September 9, 1782
  - Morris, Robert, to Abraham Yates Junr. Esquire, Contl. Loan Officer for the State of New York. "You will receive from the Treasurer of the United States a Discharge for the Bill of Exchange therein mentioned". L. S. 1 p. quarto, dated Office of Finance, October 23, 1782
  - Morris, Robert, to Abraham Yates Esqr., Loan Officer of the State of New York at Albany. "As to the request you make of Money I am very sorry to say that it is not in my Power to comply with it". L. S. 2 p. quarto, dated Office of Finance, November 29, 1782
  - Murray, Joseph addressed to William Corry Esquire, Attorney at Law in Albany. Relating to various legal cases. L. S. 2 p. folio, dated New York, August 2, 1756
  - Oothoudt, Henry, addressed to Honorable Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. & Congress, New York. "On the 17th the Convention met - 53 Members present. The Chancellor opened with a long Oration - Moved a Resolution that the Proposed plan of Government be Discussed, June 21, 1788
  - Oothoudt, Henry, addressed to Honorable Abraham Yates Junr. in Congress, New York, "Yesterday we Proceeded to the Consideration of the first Clause of the 8th Section of the first Article". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Poughkeepsie, June 27, 1788
  - Osgood, Samuel; Livingston, Walter; Lee, Arthur, Addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr., New York. "It is our Duty to remind you that until you have taken the Usual Oath of Office we cannot Consider you as a Commissioner of the Loan Office under the Ordin, March 1, 1786
  - Osgood, Samuel; Livingston, Walter; Lee, Arthur. To Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. Transmitting a Resolve of Congress in reference to the Oath of Office & returning the Oath left by Yates at the office; of the Board of Treasury. L. S. 2 p. quarto, dated Board, dated March 3, 1786
  - Petry, William; Frank, John; Fox, Friedenrich. Their appraisal of certain lands forfeited by John Tompson, Endorsed: - "The within supposed to have been sold by Gen, Gansevoort & Jeremiah Van Rensselaer". D. S. 1 p. quarto, dated Johnstown, February 10, 1785
  - Political Broadside - Announcement "To the Electors of the State of New York". Requesting the electors to support Jay and Van Rensselaer and containing the names of over 80 prominent; citizens of New York. Double page printed folio, dated February 10, 1795
  - Rogers, John, addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates, Attorney at Law in Albany, Asking information regarding some case at law. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated New York, September 24, 1768
  - Schuyler, Pieter (Mayor of Albany). A reply to Oom. Godevridus van Dell's application -in regard to the highway. A. D. S. 2 p. folio, dated, December 4, 1688
  - Schuyler, Philip; Ten Broeck, Abraham; Livingston, Peter R. Addressed to Abraham Yates Esq., Chairman of the Committee of Correspondence, Albany. Interesting letter relative to Important decisions of the House of Assembly. "You will at one glance perceive, February 25, 1774
  - Silvester, Peter. Bill of costs in suit of Janneke Van Hoosen against Dirck Van Derheyden, receipted by Silvester as attorney for Defendant. D. S. 1 p. quarto, dated May 19, 1767
  - Silvester, Peter, addressed to The Honble Abraham Yates Esqr., New York, Concerning the overpayment of a certain Mr. Beache. A L. S. 1 p. folio dated Kinderhook, June 19, 1787
  - Six Nations Endorsed: "Answer of the Six Nations to the Speech of the 12 United Colonies 1775"
    Document 3 p. quarto, part of it in the autograph of Abm. Yates Junr. Also, Document, 1 p, quarto, endorsed: - "Speech to the Indiana when they rec'd the Presents.
  - Smith, Melancton, addressed to The Honl. Abraham Yates Junr. Esq., Poughkeepsie. "Report here said that you was defunct and that your funeral had been solemnized with great pomp. We have nothing authentic from the Convention of Massachusetts. The decision, January 23, 1968
  - Smith, Melancton, addressed to The Honl. Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Poughkeepsie refers to the adoption of the Constitution. "He advises that the Sun granted as a donation should be acknowledged as a debt, and included in the Obligations given to the Cour, January 28, 1788
  - Smith, William, addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., in Albany. Refers to his serious illness and sending remembrances to his friends in Albany. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manr. St. George, July 18, 1786
  - Smith, William, to Abraham Yates Esqr. Refers to the New Constitution. "It Strikes me with amusement that Good Whigs who Suffered and underwent what they Did Should turn tall too". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manr. St. George, June 12, 1783
  - Swart, Dirck, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. at Albany. Referring to 5 Plates sent up to Yates by Esq. Fonda's Sloop. Also Bill for same, oblong strip in Dirck Swart's autograph. autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated Manor Livingston, March 18, 1756
  - Taylor, William, addressed to Mr. Ome La Grange Living at the Hellebargh. Mentioning his father's will & advising him to subject Ary La Grange to a strict cross-questioning regarding the same, autograph letter signed 1 p. folio dated Hellebargh, March 23, 1768
  - Ten Broeck, Abraham (Chairman). Abraham Yates Junr's license for six years to use the books of the Albany Library. Also signed by James Van Ingen, Treasurer. D. S. 1 small square printed from, dated, April 19, 1793
  - Ten Broeck, Abraham, Printed Broadside, recommending Gen, Philip Schuyler as a Candidate for the vacant seat of a Member of Senate. Signed by Abm, Ten Broeck as Chairman. '1 p. folio, dated In Committee Albany, April 2, 1795
  - Ten Broeck, Dirck, addressed to the Honbl Abraham Yates Junr. Esquire, Albany, Referring to some document which he enclosed in the letter. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Albany, June 16, 1791
  - Ten Broeck, Dirck, to the Honbl, Abm, Yates Junr. Esqr. An acknowledgment of his error in Judgment as an Inspector of Election in not allowing Abraham Yates' suffrage. A. D. S. 2 p. folio, dated Albany, June 16, 1791
  - Ten Broeck, Dirck. An acknowledgment of his error in refusing Yates 'vote & agreeing to pay all the costs of the suit brought against him by Yates. A. D. S. 1 p. folio, dated July 25, 1791
  - Ten Eyck, Henry, Junr. His receipt for 42 pounds 6 shillings. D. S. 2 p. quarto, dated May 14, 1771
  - Ten Eyck, Jacob C. (Judge). Affidavit of Christian Ehl in his case against Thomas Winn. D. S. 1 p. folio, dated May 25, 1765
  - Ten Eyck, John (Recorder). Bill of costs in the suit of Andries Wies against Sybrant G. Van Schaick. D. S. 1 small piece, no date, about, 1754 (?)
  - Van Eps, John E., addressed to Mr. Abrun Yates, attorney at Lew at Albany, to the care of Joseph Yates at Schonechdadie. Mentions Andries Gardinier and his brother Jacob, autograph letter signed in Dutch, 1 p. folio, dated Cagenuwaga, May 22, 1760
  - Van Rensselaer, Jeremiah, addressed to Robert Yates Esqr., Attorney at Law, Albany. Asking him to arrest immediately one Jacob of Cloverack. "John McCombes has Settled with me". autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated New York, September 9, 1764
  - Van Renssealaer, Jeremiah, to Abraham Yates Junr. "The Montgomery Delegates are Expected in town this Evening. Judge Oothoudt, the Mayor and such others as May be Ready Embark this Evening With Capt. Van Wosrt for Poughkeepsie. autograph letter signed 1 p, June 13, 1788
  - Van Rensselaer, Stephen. Receipt given Abraham Yates Junr D. S. 1 p. folio in autograph of & also signed by Peter W. Yales, dated September 17, 1764
  - Van Schaick, Wessel, Two Bills of Exchange drawn on Messrs. Sargent Chambers & Co., Merchants to London, in favor of him & signed by Reade & Yates. D. 1 p. quarto, dated New York, August 24, 1770
  - Visscher, Matthew, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. An interesting letter, narrating the experiences of Maj. Bigelow, who was sent with a flag. from, our Army to the Commander of the British Troop We were mads to believe that the Americans were mean, August 19, 1776
  - Visscher, Matthew, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Kingston. Interesting letter referring to the condition of Schoharie, mentioning Gen. Arnold as "gone to the westward" & repeating Col. Willett's Interesting description of affaire at Fort Schuyle, August 15, 1777
  - Visscher, Matthew, to Abraham Yates Esq. Refers to a Petition of George G. Klock's & touches upon many political points. "Does not the Confederation expressly declare that Delegates shall be annually appointed, and take their Seats in Congress on the firs, dated March 6, 1786
  - Visscher, Matthew, addressed to Ab. Yates Junr., John McKesson and Melancton Smith esqr., New York. "The Antifederalists had a Majority in every District except the City of Albany". autograph letter signed 2 p. folio, dated May 30, 1788
  - Wendell, Evertä draft of Indenture between him- And Hendrick Wendell of Sinckchaick, of the one part, and John Johannis Fonda, son of Susanna, one of the daughters of Abm. Wendell dec'd, of the Colony of Rensselaer Wyck, of the other part. Document, part, dated June 1767; 3 pages folio
  - Wendell, Harmanus. Draft of his Will. Signed by Jacob Pruyn, John Ja. Lansingh & Pet. Silvester as witnesses. D. S. 2 p. folio, dated April 18, 1757
  - Wendell, Harmanus. Memorial addressed by Harmanus Wendell, Lucas Van Veghten & another to Sir Jeffery Amherst, Commander in Chief of all his Majesties forces in America, requesting a Pass to go from Albany to Montreal, Draft of Document in autograph of Ab, dated January 23, 1762
  - Wendell, Harmanus. Draft of his Will, part of it in the autograph of Abraham Yates Junr. D. 4 p. folio, dated May 25, 1769
  - Wendell, Harmanue H., addressed to his father, "Harmanus Wendell, Merchant in Albany "Mr. John Fry telse me he has been Drunk For Six Weeks upon a Stretch and is So Every Day". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Schenectady, January 16, 1762
  - Wendell, Henry I, addressed to Abraham Yates Esq., Sheriff In Albany
    "Lord How has Ordered me Immediately to Proceed With my Company and Complete it upon the Mohawk River". Autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated Albany, April 4, 1758.
  - Werth, Johan Jacob, Addressed to Mstr. Abraham Yates, Scheriff living in Albany. Reminding him of his promise to send the under-sheriff to Schoharie. autograph letter signed in Dutch, 1 p. folio, dated Schocharie, April 9, 1757
  - Whitney, Thomas, addressed to Abraham Yates Esq, at Albany. Asking him to "take Cear of two "Rites". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated' Clouvriack, October 6, 1760
  - Whitney, Thomas, to Abraham Yates Junr. Telling him. he had settled his Action with Robert Noble. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Clouvarieck, October 29, 1760
  - Williston, John, addressed to Mr. Yates att Albany, Atorney att Law. Asking advice as to how he should proceed in his action with Parsons. autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated Springfield, July 18, 1764
  - Winn, John, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. Asking him. to call on him as soon as possible to give him advice regarding action toward his creditors. autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Albany City Hall, May 8, 1773
  - Winne Anthonoy addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates at Albany, Requesting him to collect from Peter Brandt the money ha was owing Winne for a load of hay. autograph letter signed 1 p. small quarto, dated Cosakkey, September 5, 1769
  - Winne, Jellis. His Bill against Abm. Yates Junr., the same being receipted July 10, 1765. A. D. S. in Dutch, 1 p. small quarto, dated January 1765
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter In his autograph to - -. Relative to the sale of land. autograph letter signed 2 p. folio, dated Albany, October 29, 1760
  - Yates, Abraham; Junr., draft of letter in his autograph to Robert Livingston Junr. Long interesting letter relating to the Elections in Albany, Mentions Abraham Ten Broeck's dishonorable conduct toward Yates, Sir Willian Johnson's influence &c. 6 p. folio, dated February 16, 1761
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr, Endorsed: - "A. Yates' Junrs. observation on Limits of the City 1761" "We are apprehensive that we will be obliged to contend with this Inhabitants of Schenectady about the Bounds and Jurisdiction of our City". D. 4 p. folio, dated A, February 21, 1761
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter in his autograph to Robert Livingston Junr, Refers to the division of a Patent "that Joins on the Half noon. "Anthony Van Schayck Brake the chain after some Discourse about the, Consequences of Stepping the Commissio, dated September 27, 1762
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter in his autograph to Samuel Dunham. Relative to his suit with Thomas Smith Junr. of Charles Town, South Carolina. 1 p. quarto, dated September 13, 1764
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr. His affidavit relative to the head of a wolf brought before him by Michael Lansing A. D. S. l small square, dated November 4, 1766
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter in his autograph to Alexander McKay. Relative to his various legal suits. 2 p. quarto, dated Albany, February 8, 1768
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to Mr. Hyde, Son of Capt. Hide, at Sarachtoge, Behind Walran Cluto. Requesting him to come down, get his Lease & pay the Debt which his father owed. L. S. 1 p. quarto, dated Albany, April 11 1769
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr. to Saml. Jones Esqr. in behalf of Corporation Requesting his opinion in a case. Autograph letter, draft of, dated February 3, 1771
  - Yates, Abraham Junr. Relating to the first settlement of Albany. "I now propose to add the reasons that induces me to think that the West India Company by Virtue of their Grant from the States of Holland had no right to the Possessions, Commons &c of the, March 19, 1771
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr. Complaint made by John Mohawney, through Abraham Yates, his attorney, against Benjamin Springer for failure to pay him various sums of money borrowed from said Mohawney.. D. 3 p. folio, dated June 1772
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr. draft of letter in his autograph. Endorsed "to Rt Yates". (Robert Yates). Concerning the sale of some wins. Small square piece, dated Albany, June 10, 1776
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr. addressed to the Committee of Albany
    Also signed by Mat. Adgate & Jno. J. Bleecker. "Yesterday a Committee was appointed to draw up a Resolve- to Put you under a Peremptory Rule to furnish the Congress with your Proceedings against Abm. Cuyler, Henry Cuyler, John Duncan, Stephan De Lancey, Benj. Hilton & John Monier". D. S. 1 p. folio, dated July 26, 1776. Yates Abraham Junr. draft of constitution N. Y. [1777] (See p. 19 of this list) Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter in his autograph, to James Duane Esq. Refers to his disappointment in not being appointed Receiver of Taxes. "I have had the Loan Office over three years without a Copper in pay". 2 p. folio, dated Albany, Sept. 7 1782.
  - Yates, Abraham, Junr., to The Honble Robert Morris Esq., Superintendent of Finance. Refers to a Bill of Exchange which he will transmit with the Returns for the present month. Draft of letter, 1 p. quarto, dated Albany, September 21, 1782